PRASHANT KUMAR RAI (1) Featured

Consultant seeking roles in Software Development, Software Design, IT Project Management, Requirement Analysis, Application Architecture, Software Support, CSS, Bootstrap, jQuery, ASP. Net, HTML, MVC



Current Designation: Consultant-IT Total Experience: 4 Year(s) 6 Month(s) Current Company: Genpact Headstrong Capital Markets Highest Degree: MCA [Computers]

Current Location: Delhi

Pref. Location: Bengaluru / Bangalore, Chandigarh, Delhi / NCR Functional Area: IT Software - Application Programming /

Maintenance

Role: Software Developer

Industry: IT-Software/Software Services

Marital Status: Single/unmarried

Key Skills: Consultant.Software Developer.Software Development.Software Design.IT Project Management.Requirement

Analysis, Application Architecture, Software Support, CSS, Bootstrap, ¡Query, ASP. Net, HTML, MVC

Verified: **Phone Number**

Last Active: 21-Jan-21 Last Modified: 21-Jan-21

Summary

A self-motivated and hardworking professional with 4.3 years of experience in Software development & support. Considerable experience in C#, Asp.net MVC, Web API 2 JQuery, JavaScript, HTML 5, Jira, TFS (Team Foundation Server).

Experience in writing stored procedures, functions, views, indexes and triggers with MS SQL Server and SSIS, SSRS implementation with MS business intelligence development studio.

Designed Application Architecture following Design Patterns and Agile Methodologies.

Well versed in tracing back data issues/errors in the Application and analyzing using SQL.

Prepared Low Level Design documents, Test cases and Unit Testing.

Excellent Communication, Analytic, Interpersonal and Presentation skills.

Work Experience

Genpact Headstrong Capital Markets as Consultant-IT Nov 2019 to Till Date

Morganstanley WM (current) Morgan Stanley is world's leading multinational investment bank and financial services company.

Involved in Wealth Management application enhancement development.

Responsible for develop modules, code quality checks, maintainability and code refactoring/testing.

HCL Technologies Ltd as Software Engineer

Jun 2016 to Nov 2019

Project: Campaign Manager, hearsaysocial Date: Dec 2019 - Till date

Role: Developer /Maintenance

Project Description: Both are the applications are used by Financial advisors to set the campaign and to convert

regular client for the firm. Roles and Responsibilities:

? Involved in Wealth Management application enhancement and Support/enhancement.

Project: AIC Date: sep 2018 - Oct 2019

Role: Developer / Enhancement

Project Description: It is a ASSET information center project. It is a web based project for managing movement of

demanding products of organization UMG.

Roles and Responsibilities:

Responsible for develop modules, code quality checks, maintainability and code refactoring/testing.

Also migrated data from other data source to AIC system through SSIS tasks.

Technologies used like MVC, SQL server, Jquery.

Also worked on code optimization, peer code review and maintaining code quality.

Created barcode for assets in AIC system using code 128 in SSRS

Project: Customer Portal Date: Apr 2018- sep 2018

Role: Support/Maintenance

Project Description: It is an internal web based project. It is a web based project for managing product sell and

distributor details.

Roles and Responsibilities:

Basic responsibilities include requirement gathering, technical analysis of feature implementation and

impact analysis of any change.

Developed SSRS report for invoice generation after purchase completion.

Technologies used like ASP.net, SQL server, Jquery.

Project: Price Date: jul 2017- Apr 2018

Role: Support/Maintenance

Project Description: It's intranet web application. This application manages pricing of the musical products related

work in organization UMG. Roles and Responsibilities:

Involved in developing small Enhancement in User Interface, using HTML, JavaScript/JQuery/HTML5

Acknowledging users and solve if any issue raise in application.

Responsible for creating and managing SQL tables and scripts.

Involved in requirement gathering, technical analysis of feature implementation and impact analysis of any change.

Education

UG: BCA (Computers) from AVK College, Bangalore in 2010

PG: MCA (Computers) from The Oxford College of Engineering in 2014

IT Skills

Skill Name	Version Last Used Experience
C# , .Net Framework 4.6 , MVC	
ASP.Net Web API , JavaScript	
JQuery ,Asp.net ,HTML , Core	
CSS	

Affirmative Action

Physically Challenged: No